Esteban David Lasso López

+491777504296 <u>estebannl28@gmail.com</u> <u>www.linkedin.com/in/esteban-lasso-lópez28</u> <u>estebanlasso.com</u> Berlin, Germany

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Over 5+ years of experience. I am a self-taught Software Engineer with more than +10 passion projects and side projects. I have worked as a freelancer doing marketing strategies and web design. I have experience as a Front-End and Back-end developer. I am detail-oriented Game Programmer accustomed to working in fast-paced and deadline-driven environments. I am confident in many programming languages, frameworks, systems, and development tools. I like to write clean code following good practices. You can find my most relevant projects on my website

EMPLOYMENT & EXPERIENCE

Rave.Space GmbH

Software Developer

August 15 2022 – Present

RaveSpace crafts virtual worlds with massive multiplayer live events and web technologies.

- Worked with front-end frameworks like Vue, React JS, and web technologies like HTML, CSS, SCSS, Javascript, Typescript, Websockets, Express
 JS, Vite, and GraphQI.
- Worked with back-end databases like Redis, Postgres SQL, and frameworks like Supabase.
- Designed systems using Object Oriented Programming in the Typescript language.
- Developed and designed several systems that have increased the functionality of the Rave Engine©. This includes several core systems required in game engines like camera, HID input, navigation, physics, game loop, and many other gameplay functionalities.
- Designed and continuously developed a custom multiplayer server with dynamic load and multi-project support. Using the Colyseus framework.
- Develop several projects, with the main focus on creating interactive 3D spaces with social capabilities (voice and video chat) and multiplayer gameplay.
- Worked with GraphQL to integrate headless CMS to be reusable in projects.
- Collaborated with colleagues to continuously improve the development process and maximize efficiency.
- Worked closely in the development stage of many core functionalities and services.

MishkiYaku Coffee Berlin, Germany
Web Developer and Designer February 2021 – July 2022

An e-commerce platform with the vision to import the best Ecuadorian coffee to Germany. Environmentally friendly and connected to non-profit projects. Awarded the mention on entrepreneurship from the Ecuadorian Embassy in Germany.

- Implemented over +12 pages in English and German from concept through deployment.
- Modified over +10 CMS elements to make the structure more client-friendly and easier to manage for larger datasets, accounting for a 30% less work per item.
- Improved SEO statues with a 50% of better Google ranking using structured data.
- Created +20 interactive elements to make the site more dynamic and attractive.
- Prototyped using Figma to present design ideas to the client and receive feedback.

Freie Universität Berlin

Summer Research Student

Berlin, Germany

June 2019 – July 2019

Summer research stay at the Freie Universität Berlin done parallel to my bachelor's studies. The main area of research was silver nanoparticles, the development of silver nanocomposites, and their possible applications in sensing.

- Elaborated reports and presentations to discuss findings performed in the laboratory.
- Worked more than +120 hours in the laboratory on the synthesis and characterization of Triangular Silver Nanoplates.
- Analyzed over +12 samples using Raman spectroscopy and cyclic voltammetry.
- Performed rigorous measurements that counted for up to 4 times per sample using cyclic voltammetry.
- Analyzed the data and plotted more than +11 graphs using software and relevant equations.

Roche Ecuador S.A Quito, Ecuador Intern – Dual Program October 2012 – August 2014

World's largest biotech companies, as well as a leading provider of in-vitro diagnostics and a global supplier of transformative innovative solutions across major disease areas.

- Worked alongside HR department, Communication Department, Purchasing Department, and Business Development Department.
- Made strategies to minimize repetitive task and improve performance, reducing 20% of time waste.
- Created over +30 internal communication emails and announcements.
- Managed more than +10 buying orders, working directly with suppliers to attend to the company's request.
- Participated in every step of acquiring assets process inside the company.

EDUCATION

Yachay Tech

University Urcuquí, Ecuador

Bachelor of Science in Engineer in Nanotechnology 2014 – 2020

ITSA (Instituto Tecnológico Superior Alemán)

Quito, Ecuador

Bürokaufmann 2012 – 2014

CERTIFICATION

Back End Development and APIs from freeCodeCamp 2022

Front End Development Libraries from freeCodeCamp 2021

Learn React Course from Code Academy 2021

JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures from freeCodeCamp 2021

Responsive Web Design from freeCodeCamp 2021

SKILLS

Languages: Spanish Native language, English C1, German B2.

Programming: C, C#, Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, HTML, CSS, SCSS, Haskell, HLSL.

Testing: Jest

Frameworks: React, Vue, Supabase, Nuxt. Package-Managers: NPM, YARN, PIP

Design and editing: Adobe Illustrator, Figma, Photoshop

Engineering: Matlab, Mathematica. **3d-Software:** Blender, Unity

Databases: MongoDB, Firebase database, PostgreSQL, MySQL, DynamoDB

Administrative: Google G Suite, Microsoft 365.

CONTESTS

Jump
Lead UI Designer and Android Developer

Lima, Peru

2018

A start-up app idea. Participated for funding in the event ``TuApp" Lima-Perú, 2018. The app will help people find jobs online as a freelance with the concept of time banks that can be use to trade for other type of work.

- Designed complete UI from concept through deployment, including logo design, typography and color palette.
- Created +20 UI elements and +8 pages using Adobe Illustrator and Photoshop.
- Programmed the UI using Ionic Framework.

Yupana Ocaña, Colombia

Lead UI Designer and Android Developer

2017

A start-up app idea. Participated for funding in the event ``TuApp" Ocaña-Colombia, 2017. The app will be a tool for students to perform basic algebra, and as a polynomial solver.

- Designed complete UI from concept through deployment, including logo design, typography and color palette.
- Created +15 UI elements including nav bar, navigation buttons, menus using Adobe Illustrator and Photoshop.
- Programmed the UI using Android Studio.

PROJECTS

Social App

Full Stack Project 2021

A social network clone created with firebase service that allows users to authenticate add information to his profile like profile picture and a description text.

• Coded 100% of the project. Meaning both back and front end.

Ride to the Heave

WebGL Videogame GMTK Gam Jam

2020 Entry for the GAMEJAM GMTKL 2020. A 2D platformer game.

- Coded 50% of the game including areas like UI, mechanics and game logic.
- Designed all the UI elements and playable sprites for the videogame.

Jumpy

WebGL Videogame

2021

A 2D platformer game.

- Coded 100% of the game including areas like UI, mechanics and game logic.
- Designed all the UI elements and playable sprites for the videogame.

SCIENTIFIC PUBLICATIONS

- Benalcázar, J., Lasso, E. D., Ibarra-Barreno, C. M., Arcos Pareja, J. A., Vispo, N. S., Chacón-Torres, J. C., & Briceño, S. (2022). Photochemical Optimization of a Silver Nanoprism/Graphene Oxide Nanocomposite's Antibacterial Properties. ACS omega.
- Arcos-Pareja, José et al. (2021). "Revealing the Synthesis of Triangular Silver Nanoplates: A Study of the Photochemical Growth Mechanism around the pH and Trisodium Citrate Variations". In: physica status solidi (b) 258.12, p. 2100189.
- Ramos, Anthony et al. (2018). "Studies on the structure and electronic properties of Linear Chitosan-Silver nano-composite for biosensor applications". In: 2018 IEEE Third Ecuador Technical Chapters Meeting (ETCM). IEEE, pp. 1-4.